There is a world hidden within our own.
The Mortal Instruments: City of Bones is a fantasy,
action, mystery film directed by Harald Zwart.
In New York City, Clary Fray, a seemingly ordinary teenager, learns that she is descended from a
line of Shadowhunters — half-angel warriors who protect humanity from evil forces.
After her mother disappears, Clary joins forces with a group of Shadowhunters and enters
Downworld, an alternate realm filled with demons, vampires, and a host of other creatures.
Clary and her companions must find and protect an ancient cup
that holds the key to her mother's future.
Clary Fray, played by Lily Collins.
Jace Wayland, played by Jamie Campbell Bower.
Simon Lewis, played by Robert Sheehan.
Alec Lightwood, played by Kevin Zegers.
Isabelle Lightwood, played by Jemima West.
Jocelyn Fray, played by Lena Headey.
The Mortal Instruments: City of Bones is a 2013 urban fantasy film based on the
first book of The Mortal Instruments series by Cassandra Clare.
It was directed by Harald Zwart, with a script written by Jessica Postigo.
The film stars Lily Collins as Clary Fray, a teenager from New York City who meets a group of Nephilim
known as the Shadowhunters while also discovering her own heritage and her family history.
The cast also includes Jamie Campbell Bower, Robert Sheehan, Kevin Zegers, Lena Headey, Kevin Durand,
Aidan Turner, Jemima West, Godfrey Gao, CCH Pounder, Jared Harris, and Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
The film's development began when Constantin Film
optioned the film rights to the book series.
Casting announcements started in 2010, with Collins being
the first actress attached to the project.
Principal photography took place in Ontario between August and November 2012.
It is an international co-production between Canada and Germany.
The Mortal Instruments: City of Bones premiered in Los Angeles on August 12, and was released on
August 21, 2013, by Entertainment One in Canada and by Constantin Film in Germany.
It was released in the United States on the same day by Screen Gems.
The film was a box-office bomb, grossing $95.3 million worldwide against a production budget of $60 million
and received generally negative reviews from critics for its plot and lack of originality.
The film was originally intended to launch a film series and to continue with a sequel based on the second
book, City of Ashes, that was in development with Sigourney Weaver set to join the cast.
However, it was postponed indefinitely and ultimately
cancelled due to the film's poor performance.
A reboot television series, titled Shadowhunters, premiered in
2016 on Freeform and ran for three seasons.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
angel, vampire, werewolf, warlock.
The tone is mind_bending.